

Chidanand Gurudutt

Nationality: Indian Date of birth: 9 Sep 1997 Gender: Male

Capacita Spring Phone number: (+91) 8105956021

Email address: chidanandgurudutt@gmail.com

• Home: #580 21st Main 4th T Block Jayanagar, 560041 Bangalore (India)

ABOUT ME

A self-taught designer, with a passion for crafting research-driven products that are simple and intuitive. My goal is to design products that manage to hit the sweet spot between business and user needs. My keen interest also lies in User Experience Design, User Analysis, and Storytelling. I am enthusiastic about pursuing a Master's Degree, where I aim to further refine and augment my existing expertise and skills.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

Bachelor of Engineering

AMC Engineering College [1 Aug 2015 - 1 Jul 2019]

City: Bangalore
Country: India

Website: https://vtu.ac.in/

Field(s) of study: Electronics and Communication

Final grade: 7.91

NQF Level: 8 - Type of credits: CGPA

Pre University Education Certificate

Jyothy Kendriya Vidyalaya Composite PU College [1 May 2014 – 1 Mar 2015]

City: Bangalore Country: India

Website: https://jyothyvidyalaya.org

Field(s) of study: Science

Final grade: 83%

Karnataka Secondary Education Examination Board

Vijaya High School [1 Jun 2012 - 1 Apr 2013]

City: bangalore Country: India

Website: https://kseab.karnataka.gov.in/english

Final grade: 87%

WORK EXPERIENCE

UI/UX Design Intern

Cureya [23 Jun 2022 – 23 Oct 2022]

City: Bangalore Country: India

Website: https://cureya.in/

Name of unit or department: UI/UX Design - Business or sector: Human health and social work activities

- Designed an interactive user interface for the mobile application.
- Worked on designing low-fidelity wireframes from user research.
- Worked on customer analysis and user testing by conducting interviews with the users.

Digital Media Designers

Safal Future [1 Nov 2019 – 30 May 2022]

City: Bangalore
Country: India

Business or sector: Education

- Designed and Developed social media kit.
- Led the video production process(Pre-production, lighting, audio, editing, color-correction, exporting) which led to an increase in viewership by 20%.
- Worked on ideating and strategizing content for the social media platforms.
- Worked on analyzing data from social media platforms to improve SEO, user acquisition, and user retention.
- Worked on re-designing the website.

Project Intern

Bosch Automotive Electronics India [16 Aug 2018 – 15 Apr 2019]

City: Bangalore Country: India

- Programmed communication protocol
- Designed a dashboard for the in-house web application.

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): Kannada

Other language(s):

English Hindi

LISTENING C2 READING C2 WRITING C1 LISTENING C1 READING C1 WRITING C1

SPOKEN PRODUCTION C1 SPOKEN INTERACTION C1 SPOKEN PRODUCTION C1 SPOKEN INTERACTION C1

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user; B1 and B2: Independent user; C1 and C2: Proficient user

DIGITAL SKILLS

Visual

Adobe Prmiere Pro / Photoshop / Canva

Interactive

Figma & Adobe XD / HTML / CSS

Programing Language

Python / C++

CONFERENCES AND SEMINARS

6th International Conference on Multidisciplinary Research

[Osmania University Campus, Hyderabad, 30 May 2019 – 31 May 2019]

"An Automated Real-Time Monitoring and Triggering of Failures

during Manufacturing Process - ANDON"

Link: http://conferenceworld.in/Conference.php?cID=1281

5th National Conference on VLSI, Communication and Computer networks (VCCN -5)

[Bangalore, 26 May 2017 - 26 May 2017]

"IoT based home automation system"

TRAINING EXPERIENCE

Growth Hacking Mentorship

[3 Aug 2022 - 3 Oct 2022]

- The Growth Hacking Mentorship is an 8-week intensive program designed specifically to grow business faster
- Topics like Customer Lifecycle, Acquisition, Retention, Email Marketing, User Onboarding, and Building landing pages were covered in this program.

Machine Learning Foundation

[28 Jun 2018 - 28 Oct 2018]

- Machine Learning Foundation is a part of the Bridge Student Accelerator Program designed to provide hands-on experience in emerging technology for students exploring different fields.
- Topics like Data cleaning, Visualization, and data interpretation using different Machine Learning models in Python were covered in this program.

HOBBIES AND INTERESTS

Basketball

- Captained the college basketball team to glory, hoisting the trophy in several prestigious tournaments.
- Currently playing for a local basketball club and have taken part in multiple state tournaments.

Running Enthusiast

• Took part in multiple 10K runs organised in Bangalore